<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infra | Academic</title>
    <link>/category/infra/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/infra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Infra</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Infra</title>
      <link>/category/infra/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Data Infrastructures in Europe</title>
      <link>/post/admin_infra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/admin_infra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been busy developing the Dutch national infrastructure for social science and a large part of that infrastructure centers around access to administrative data. We have world class partners in CBS (Statistics Netherlands) who have continued to improve access to administrative data over the last 15 years such that researchers in the Netherlands can now access hundreds of datasets through a secure remote access environment and this has already led to publications in leading social science journals and closer collaborations between government and the research community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODISSEI has an auxillary role in this. ODISSEI does not hold any data or provide access. What ODISSEI does do is to try and further enhance the researchers experience in using administrative data. We have increase the computational power that is available to researchers, we are improving the findability of data within CBS through an ODISSEI portal, and we are ensuring that a wider range of external data can be linked to the catalogue of data that CBS holds. These are tasks that CBS not only does not have the budget to do, but also does not have the mandate to do. In that sense, ODISSEI is the interface between administrative data of government and the research community themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of countries have identified the same problem and come to different solutions about how to improve researchers access to administrative data. In this post I am going to give a run down of the initiatives that I am aware of and my understanding of how and why they differ from the work that we do. I finish up at the end by laying out how these initiatives can be brought together and the added benefits of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
